Guide to the Yale University Corporation Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Corporation meeting and retreat background materials, 1992-1999; Accession 2009-A-149
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1993 November 18-20
    - Strategic Plan Fall 1993, 1993 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - miscellaneous materials, 1993 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1994 January 21
    - correspondence, UC Final Reports and Interim Reports,materials from table, 1994 January 21 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1994 February 25-26
    - working papers, 1994 February 25-26 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Notebook materials, 1994 February 25-26 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Committee of the Whole folder - correspondence, votes, Minutes, notes, 1994 February 25-26 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Forestry Strategic Plan Fall 1993, 1994 February 25-26 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1994 April 14-16
    - Minutes and supporting materials for Minutes, 1994 April 14-16 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - supporting materials for mailing, 1994 April 14-16 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - supporting materials for meeting, 1994 April 14-16 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1994 May 21
    - Yale Corporation Meeting Mailing, 1994 May 21 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Alumni Leadership binder, 1994 May 21 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - materials from meeting, Minutes, appointments, 1994 May 21 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1994 June 24-26
    - Yale Corporation Meeting Mailing, 1994 June 24-26 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Agenda, appointments, Minutes, votes, correspondence, other supporting materials, 1994 June 24-26 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Working papers, 1994 June 24-26 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1994 September 23-24
    - supporting materials for meeting, 1994 September 23-24 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - supporting materials for meeting, 1994 September 23-24 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1994 December 10
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1994 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Agendas, Minutes, correspondence, 1994 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1994 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Audit Committee Meeting binder materials, 1994 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Buildings and Grounds Meeting - New York, 1995 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1995 February 25
    - Working Papers, 1995 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Conflict of Interest Policies, 1995 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1995 April 20-22
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1995 April 20-22 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Working Papers, 1995 April 20-22 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1995 May 20-22
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1995 May 20-22 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Audit Committee Meeting binder materials, 1995 May 20-22 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Working Papers, 1995 May 20-22 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Telephonic Meeting, 1995 August 23 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1995 September 24
    - Minutes, agendas, supporting materials, 1995 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Yale Corporation 1995 Retreat mailing, 1995 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Working Papers, 1995 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1995 November 17
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1995 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Consent Agenda, 1995 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Materials from table, 1995 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Audit Committee Meeting binder Material, 1995 November 20 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting - New York, NY, 1996 January 12
    - Draft Minutes, 1996 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1996 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Finance Committee materials, 1996 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Binder for meeting, 1996 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1996 February 1-3
    - Draft Minutes, 1996 February 1-3 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Materials from table, 1996 February 1-3 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1996 February 1-3 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Background documents for the Yale Corporation's Discussion of Tobacco at the Plenary Discussion on February 2, 1996, 1996 February 1-3 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Yale University School of Medicine Programs and Services, 1996 February 1-3 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1996 April 19-20
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1996 April 19-20 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Audit Committee binder, 1996 April 19-20 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Minutes, 1996 April 19-20 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1996 May 26
    - Working Papers, 1996 May 26 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1996 May 26 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1996 June 7-8
    - Minutes Draft, 1996 June 7-8 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Materials from table, 1996 June 7-8 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Proposal to establish the Office of University Properties, 1996 June 7-8 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1996 June 7-8 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Notebook materials, 1996 June 7-8 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Yale Corporation Retreat, 1996 September 27-29
    - Corporation Retreat Materials binders, 1996 September 27-29 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Retreat Materials, 1996 September 27-29 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1996 September 27-29 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting - Mailing, 1996 December 5-7 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1997 February 20-22
    - Materials from table, 1997 February 20-22 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1997 February 20-22 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Extra binder materials, 1997 February 20-22 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1997 April 10-12
    - Plenary Session materials, 1997 April 10-12 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Materials from table, 1997 April 10-12 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1997 April 10-12 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Tercentennial planning materials, 1997 April 10-12 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Working Papers, 1997 April 10-12 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1997 May 25
    - Materials from table and notebooks, 1997 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Working Papers, 1997 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1997 June 13-14
    - Consent and Secretary's Agendas, 1997 June 13-14 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Health Vote, 1997 June 13-14 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Working Papers, 1997 June 13-14 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Meeting logistics, 1997 June 13-14 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting/Retreat, Aspen, CO, 1997 September 20
    - Yale Corporation Retreat The Internationalization of Yale binder, 1997 September 20 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Minutes, Agendas, 1997 September 20 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1997 September 20 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1997 October 13
    - Minutes, 1997 October 13 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Attachment A, 1997 October 13 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1997 November 20-22
    - Notebook materials, 1997 November 20-22 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1998 February 19-21
    - News clippings, materials from table, correspondence, 1998 February 19-21 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Audit Committee binder, 1998 February 19-21 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Attachment A - Yale University Patent Policy, 1998 February 19-21 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1998 April 16-18
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1998 April 16-18 (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Yale Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Corporation Meeting 4/17/98 binder, 1998 April 16-18 (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1998 May 24
    - Survey of Alumni/ae Communications, 1998 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Three Concentric Circles documents, 1998 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Material from notebooks, 1998 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1998 June 18-20
    - Supplement for EPC discussion of BBS, 1998 June 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - The Operating and Capital Budget 1998-99, 1998 June 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - School of Medicine Strategic Facilities Plan, 1998 June 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Working Papers, 1998 June 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Extra Papers, 1998 June 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Telephonic Yale Corporation Meeting, 1998 August 25
    - Minutes and supporting materials, 1998 August 25 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1998 September 26
    - Audit Committee Materials, 1998 September 26 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Buildings and Grounds and EPC Votes, 1998 September 26 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - President and Provost Agendas, and Minutes, 1998 September 26 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1998 December 5
    - Minutes and Agendas, 1998 December 5 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Affirmative Action Report, 1998 December 5 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Finance Committee materials, 1998 December 5 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Materials from table, 1998 December 5 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1999 February 18-20
    - Minutes and Votes, 1999 February 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - University Council Update 1997-1998, 1999 February 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Working Papers, 1999 February 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1999 February 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Materials from table, 1999 February 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1999 April 8-10
    - Minutes / Working papers, 1999 April 8-10 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1999 April 8-10 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting - Minutes and working papers, 1999 May 23 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting, 1999 June 10-12
    - Office of the Provost Operating and Capital Budget 1999-2000, 1999 June 10-12 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Notebook materials, 1999 June 10-12 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting / Retreat, 1999 September 30 - October 3
    - Audit Committee binder, 1999 September 30 - October 3 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Supporting materials for meeting, 1999 September 30 - October 3 (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Yale Corporation Meeting
- Corporation records, 1976-2005; Accession 2010-A-067
  - Standing, Special, and Appt. Committees, 1998 December-2005 February (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Report on the New Residential Colleges Study, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yale Corporation Charter and Legislation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - In Remembrance of our friend Bart Giamatti, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yale Corp ByLaws, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yale Corp ByLaws, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Regulations, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yale University Reserve Officers Training Corps and Military Educational Assistance, 2002 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Fellow Elections
    - 2002 Alumni Fellow Election articles and correspondence, 2002 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 2003 Alumni Fellow Election, 2003 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 14A)
    - 2004 Alumni Fellow Election biographical sketch drafts for Margaret Marshall, David A. Jones and Frederick O. Terrell, 2004 March (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 2004 Alumni Fellow Election, 2001 March (Box 1, Folder 15A)
    - Alumni Fellow Brochure, 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Affiliation Agreement, 1999 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Assessment Interviews, 1998 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ByLaws - possible modifications, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Harvard Board of Overseers Election, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Certification of By Laws, 2003 October (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Misc. Correspondence
    - Yale's wayward navigation - Open letter to all Fellows of Yale Corporation, from Robert McKinlay, 1996 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Conflict of Interest Policies, 2004 April (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Draft Response to Boston Globe re: to Corporate Governance, 2003 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Anti-Apartheid Monument to replace Shantytown on Beineke Plaza, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Yale Corporation Committees, 2001-2003 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Yale University Investment Committee
    - Executive Summary and Report, 2001 June (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Executive Summary and Report, 2002 October (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Executive Summary and Report, 2003 June (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Executive Summary and Report, 2003 October (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Executive Summary and Report, 2003 December (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Executive Summary and Report, 2004 March (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Honorary Degree Folders, 1999 May-2005 May (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Corporation records, 1984-2007; Accession 2014-A-026
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2058.
  - General
  - South Africa
    - Yale Policy and South Africa: A Report to the Yale Corporation, 1984 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Public affairs memo, 1985 November (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Divestment-Pelikan memo, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Corporation records, 1746; Accession 2015-A-042; 0.02; (1 envelope)
  - True copy of the acceptance by the Fellows of the Yale Corporation of 28 pounds, 10 shillings sterling, from Philip Livingston, Esq. for the establishment of an endowed professorship in Divinity, 1746 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)